It's not always easy to deal with what comes naturally.
Animal Behaviour is a comedy, animation film directed by David Fine.
Five animals meet regularly to discuss their inner angst
in a group therapy session led by Dr.
Clement, a canine psychotherapist.
The group includes Lorraine, a leech who suffers from separation anxiety; Cheryl, a praying mantis who can’t seem to keep a man;
Todd, a pig with an eating disorder; Jeffrey, a bird with guilt issues; and Linda, an obsessive-compulsive cat.
Dr. Clement (voice), played by Ryan Beil.
Victor (voice), played by Taz Van Rassel.
Lorraine (voice), played by Leah Juel.
Cheryl (voice), played by Andrea Libman.
Jeffrey (voice), played by James Kirk.
Linda (voice), played by Alison Snowden.
Animal sexual behaviour takes many different forms,
including within the same species.
Common mating or reproductively motivated systems include
monogamy, polygyny, polyandry, polygamy and promiscuity.
Other sexual behaviour may be reproductively motivated (e.g.
sex apparently due to duress or coercion and situational sexual
behaviour) or non-reproductively motivated (e.g.
homosexual sexual behaviour, bisexual sexual behaviour, cross-species sex,
sexual arousal from objects or places, sex with dead animals, etc.).
When animal sexual behaviour is reproductively motivated, it is often termed mating or copulation; for most non-human mammals, mating and copulation occur
at oestrus (the most fertile period in the mammalian female's reproductive cycle), which increases the chances of successful impregnation.
Some animal sexual behaviour involves competition,
sometimes fighting, between multiple males.
Females often select males for mating only if they appear
strong and able to protect themselves.
The male that wins a fight may also have the chance to mate with a larger number of
females and will therefore pass on his genes to their offspring.
Historically, it was believed that only humans and a small number of other species performed sexual acts other than for
reproduction, and that animals' sexuality was instinctive and a simple "stimulus–response" behaviour.
However, in addition to homosexual behaviours, a range of species
masturbate and may use objects as tools to help them do so.
Sexual behaviour may be tied more strongly to the establishment and maintenance of complex
social bonds across a population which support its success in non-reproductive ways.
Both reproductive and non-reproductive behaviours can be related to expressions of dominance over another
animal or survival within a stressful situation (such as sex due to duress or coercion).
The tone is lighthearted.